<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>https://en.muktomona.com/</id>
	<title />
	<link rel="self" href="https://en.muktomona.com/" />
	<rights>Copyright © 2022</rights>
	<updated>2022-11-07T22:55:54Z</updated>
	<subtitle>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</subtitle>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2022/11-01-razel-homosexuality</id>
		<title>Razel - About Homosexuality in Bangladesh</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2022/11-01-razel-homosexuality" />
		<updated>2022-11-03T01:10:24Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;~ &lt;em&gt;Md Abdul Bachith Razel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words homosexuality, transsexualism, bisexuality, heterosexuality were never coined in the Western world. On the contrary, since the birth of ancient civilization in the history of all parts of the world, Greek, Native American, Chinese, Aztex, Mayan, Egyptian civilization, the life of pagan history, the history of Arab tribes, Persian literature, in the poetic literature of the subcontinent, the prevalence of different aspects of sexuality is seen everywhere. It was not until the 19th century that the powers that be in the Western world, in pursuit of their own political interests, introduced laws and customs to limit human behavior to a limited set of rules, with the aim to subject people to certain ways of life and to constrict and control them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can give guarantees to the powerful people to gain political and economic interests. Michel Foucault developed his research in three books on the history of sexuality. In article 37, Bangladesh is part of the decision of the British Empire. India is one of our neighbors that has come out of the influence of this imperialist history and abandoned article 37 of the colonial law. More recently, Taiwan and Bhutan have also legalized consensual homosexuality. It can be noted that pedophilia or sex with children and forced rape are not encouraged and homosexuality cannot be blamed for it. For example, no one in Bangladesh blames heterosexuality for all brutal rape, violence against each other, dowry, cheating in the name of marriage and sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think that those who defend gay rights are also gay. But do those who talk about environmental protection also become plants, rivers, plastics or waste? Those who defend gay rights, talk about their human values, and they don't all have to be gay. Think of the environment backwards, if you are heterosexual and attracted to the opposite sex and this is not recognized by your society and state, you must run away and just because you are hated or rejected or even killed , but what a miserable situation that would be. Heterosexuality is a normal sexual orientation just like homosexuality, bisexuality or transgender and everyone loves the same dream and wants to be accepted. It can only be called selfishness if the rights of the majority are realized or if you don't care about the rights of others then it can be called selfishness and if you don't want the human rights of others to be realized then it can be called oppression. And rights are not about sharing a cake that you want to share with another. On the contrary, the image of equality will emerge in society, at the same time everyone's values ​​will improve, and the attitude of helping others will increase. If we are not all free together, are we really all free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those whose question is that homosexuality does not produce children, yes may not participate directly, but nature uses this trick in its need for survival. For example, if a boy is homosexual in a family, he will be more attracted to the opposite sex if a girl is born to his siblings, which will favor the reproduction of the next generation. Thanks to this natural selection, one in ten men is born with a tendency to be homosexual or attracted to the same sex. A 2004 study in Italy found that same-sex households had higher fertility rates among women. Dr. Andrea Camperio Siani's study found that while the average number of children in a heterosexual family is 2.3, the number of children in a homosexual family is 2.6. So he says,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have finally solved the paradox … the same factor that influence sexual orientation in males promotes higher fecundity in females.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientist Deinhammer also says,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is remarkably simple: the same gene that causes men to like men, also causes women to like men, and as a result to have more children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only motherhood, but love is the foundation of a successful marriage. There are many heterosexual and even lesbian couples who have childless or artificial children. We are all familiar with the test tube, the surrogacy system. Science is progressing in this regard day by day. Also, how many children born to heterosexuals grow up without parents on the streets, in disrespectful neglect or in orphanage. Adopting children in this miserable country and caring for them and raising them in the shadow of the family will not benefit society. And when same-sex relationships get social recognition, they do that adoption work.
Homosexuality is of two types, one is behavioral and the other is congenital, which is called biological hard fact. Behavioral homosexuals change their sexual behavior depending on the environment. This example can be observed among male fishermen. But those born with homosexual characteristics do not change. In October 2016, a research team led by Dr Watts from the University of Essex noticed changes in finger height due to hormonal and female hormonal differences in the baby during the womb, which also affects their sexuality later in life. Dr Watts said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research suggests that our sexuality is determined in the womb and is dependent on the amount of male hormone we are exposed to or the way our individual bodies react to that hormone, with those exposed to higher levels of testosterone being more likely to be bisexual or homosexual.… Because of the link between hormone levels and difference in finger lengths, looking at someone's hands could provide a clue to their sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the height of the fingers of homosexual men and women differs in certain aspects from that of heterosexuals.
You can read more about this research in the Archives of Sexual Behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our conservative society, which lacks education in sexual awareness, homosexuals lead a melancholy life of suppressing sexuality where the emphasis is on human values. No one wants to choose a life of harsh oppression. The lives of those 10-15% of homosexuals in our population are going through this difficult period due to the ignorant hatred of the majority of heterosexuals. Because, in our society, we grow up unknowingly learning ignorance, division, aggressive thinking and hatred from birth. For some heterosexuals, homosexuality may seem impossible, perhaps. Because he thinks about himself but no one tells him to be gay so he doesn't have to think about himself. Heterosexual sex is or should be consensual, just as homosexual sex is or should be consensual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~ Guest Writer: &lt;strong&gt;Md Abdul Bachith Razel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Volunteer
(Aiming to prevent the isolation and suicide of young LGBT+ people, aged 14 to 25, victims of homophobia or transphobia and in a situation of family breakdown)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2022/09-12-happy-birthday-avijit-roy</id>
		<title>Happy Birthday Avijit Roy</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2022/09-12-happy-birthday-avijit-roy" />
		<updated>2022-09-12T09:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy Birthday Avijit Roy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://en.muktomona.com/images/dup/Avijit_bday_2022.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We remember you. You live in the mind of every living muktomona in this world!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2022/06-03-religious-politics-india</id>
		<title>Nupur Sharma - A very familiar face of religious politics in india</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2022/06-03-religious-politics-india" />
		<updated>2022-09-11T10:53:24Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;A derogatory statement from India has recently come into spotlight in the international media as a hot potato of the world ,and Nupur Sharma, BJP Parliament member of India, claimed on her tweet that the context was during TV debate Mahadev, Hindu deity, was being disrespected and insulted. In that context, she responded using derogatory statement. Each party uses religious sentiments at the end of the day to win in the debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was not serious until few countries in middle east raise the concern and asked for boycott of Indian products. There are two consequences that we need to take into consideration. The first is economy and the second is racism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously as a whole it will have impact on the economy of India in general. Let's analyze the stakeholders who will be victimized by banning of Indian products. Apart from Hindu, there are Muslims, Sikhs, Buddha, Christian, Jews and so many other religious groups of people who are involved with businesses outside of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to one internet source, &amp;quot;India's arable land area of 159.7 million hectares (394.6 million acres) is the second largest in the world. Its gross irrigated crop area of 82.6 million hectares (215.6 million acres) is the largest in the world.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General people of India cultivate crops and send the materials to different countries. At the end of the day all these stakeholders need to suffer the problem and they had no involvement whatsoever over the statement. Obviously, Indian government is trying to take initiative already since they got international pressure over the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the racism issue would always raise upon general workers who are not much concerned about this kind of issue at all. Workers are mostly concerned with how to keep their family happy and debt free. That's all they think about. They are no way involved with national politics or no time to watch this kind of discussion. Out of nowhere they would face racism for what they do not have any idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dirty politics using religion is still ongoing in 21st century. A 15-year English medium school boy from a Hindu aristocrat family once said to me &amp;quot;This religion is just cultural garbage which I do not believe&amp;quot;. The problem is that there are 1000 religions in the world and everyone claims to have monopoly of truth and as we learned from science and reason, the credibility of these religious beliefs is not out of the topic. BJP members have tendency to use religious sentiments for last few decades. Chief Minister of West Bengal Mamata Banerjee straightforward told in media that &amp;quot;If it happened in Bengal, I would put her in jail&amp;quot;. The issue is very clear. Stop doing politics by the name of religion and young generation do understand the tricks used by these politicians. E.g. Donald Trump, who took oath putting hand on Bible, is promoting white supremacy and he is taking into consideration the national interest first over humanity. These politicians know well that the religions they hold has no monopoly of truth to certain extent as they have read religious scriptures as well as equipped with contemporary secular materialistic knowledge. Despite they use the religion just to hold into power because using religious sentiments it is easy to convince and make fool to mass people. Mass people only asks question of the credibility of these leaders when they get clear evidence of corruption. Otherwise, they do not bother with politics apart from election time. Obviously Indian ordinary people do understand these political agendas, yet they are just silent and try to avoid the issue since this is long time heritage of dirty politics. How do we solve the problem of politics by the name of religion then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, this problem needs to be solved by upcoming younger generation because we can no longer put our trust to these old hypocrites' leaders who time and again use religion into politics. We need society based on truth, humanity, reasoning and science. Sadhguru recently gave the hint,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only if the younger generation does things that the parents never imagined possible, can a society evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~ Guest Writer: &lt;strong&gt;Md Maruf Hasan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PhD candidate, Department of Usul al-Din and Comparative Religion, International Islamic University Malaysia&lt;br /&gt;
E-mail: marufenglish021 at gmail dot com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/11-01-atrocities-on-hindus-in-bangladesh-and-the-fraudulent-and-irresponsible-statement-by-the-foreign-minister-of-the-country-a-k-abdul-momen</id>
		<title>Atrocities on Hindus in Bangladesh and the Fraudulent and Irresponsible Statement by the Foreign Minister of the Country, A. K. Abdul Momen</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/11-01-atrocities-on-hindus-in-bangladesh-and-the-fraudulent-and-irresponsible-statement-by-the-foreign-minister-of-the-country-a-k-abdul-momen" />
		<updated>2021-11-01T20:53:24Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;After more than two weeks of barbaric atrocities on nonviolent and innocent Hindus by Muslim mobs in many parts of Bangladesh, the foreign minister of the country, A. K. Abdul Momen, has issued a statement in his &lt;a href="https://mofa.portal.gov.bd/site/page/6758ab52-c643-43fa-b76e-4eb99fcf5b47"&gt;ministry's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement is full of falsehood and downplaying of the atrocities on a religious minority community, obviously with two aims: 1) to deceive the community of civilized nations and 2) to encourage the domestic Islamic fanatics by signaling that the impunity that they have historically enjoyed remains in full force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually acquainted with Momen about three decades back in the greater Boston area, USA. He had a PhD degree and was teaching at a college in that area. I was teaching at Northeastern University at that time. However, I do not remember much about him, due to my limited interactions with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first and obvious question about his statement on the recent brutal atrocities on a nonviolent minority population of his country would be, why the talk from the foreign minister? The horrific incidents did not involve any foreign country or any foreign criminal or victim. The obvious answer to the question would be that he wanted to control the damage to the image of his government/nation. But, obviously, he either did not understand or did not want to acknowledge that lying is not the way to make a good image of whatever one focuses on - an individual, a family, a community, a government or a nation. A good image actually needs good thoughts and deeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let us see what Momen actually said. Without going into what I know through personal communications and through social media, let us assume that what Momen said were the facts and talk about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Momen said, &amp;quot;Contrary to all the ongoing propaganda, only 6 people died during recent violence of which 4 were Muslims, killed during the encounters with law enforcing authorities, and 2 were Hindus, one of whom had normal death and another when he jumped in a pond. None was raped and not a single Mandir was destroyed.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How dishonest and disgusting for a PhD degree holding former college professor! To Momen, 6 people being dead does not matter much! But by civilized standards, it does; the deaths of even the Muslim mob members are regrettable - the religiously brainwashed mentally sick criminals needed psychological treatments with factual and logical thoughts, not death. How idiotic that he talked about one 'normal death'. Since when a normal death of an ordinary citizen is a matter of news and attention by a government minister? How idiotic that he talked about one 'jumped in a pond'!! Did that person willingly jump in the pond for committing suicide? Was he not too scared of the barbaric mob? Again, I have argued here with the assumption that Momen's statements are factual – which in reality are far from the total facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Momen talked about the government taking immediate action and arresting the perpetrators! How many thousand did his government arrest? Why are such arrests, including the numbers, not in the newspapers in Bangladesh? Talking about actions against the barbaric acts by Muslim criminals, why is there never news in the news media about the actual punishments for similar criminals in Ramu (September 2012), Nasirnagar (October 2016), Shalla (March 2021), and in many more places in Bangladesh during governments led by Momen's party, Awami League? Of course, because no significant punishment was given to such criminals. Momen's words mean nothing but disgraceful deception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Momen talked about compensation to the victims by his government! There is a saying in Bangla, &amp;quot;vikshar dorkar nai, kutta thekao&amp;quot; (do not need the alms, restrain the dog). The disgrace of a minster obviously could not comprehend the pain and trauma of the victims! Compensation is nothing to the victims when there is no guarantee that such atrocities on them would not be repeated in the country. Even if the present places of atrocities were fortified, which is unlikely, there is no basis to think that such atrocities would not happen again soon at some other places in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minister talked about the image of his government! In international politics, world powers play games with corrupt and deplorable nations, even when they have no respect for such nations. They know what Bangladesh is, even when they do not take punitive actions against that country. Lying is not how good images can be made; good images are made through good thoughts and deeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Momen talked about his government supporting religious activities (Puja Mondop) of Hindus in Bangladesh! &lt;a href="https://www.thedailystar.net/bangladesh/news/hindu-bouddha-christian-oikya-parishad-discontented-over-poor-allocation-fund-proposed-budget-2101109"&gt;Here are a couple of facts.&lt;/a&gt; The Religious Affairs Ministry of Bangladesh has an allocation of Tk 290.08 crore for religious minorities in its most recent budget. The same budget has a total of Tk 15,054.03 crore allocated (Annual Development Program, ADP) for all religious groups, including Muslims. So, the non-Muslims of the country get just 1.9%, while they represent about 10% of the population! They are deprived of 81% of their fair share!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Momen talked about the Quran being placed near the feet of a deity sparking outrage in the country - meaning too many Muslims with too much of Islamic sentiments would be too angered over the matter! Obviously, no Hindu in his right mind could have done that, as they are fully aware of the excessive Islamic sentiments in the country, which have been behind the Muslim mobs making their life hell in their homeland of centuries. Indeed, no Hindu did it; it was done by a Muslim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But who are behind the excessive Islamic sentiments in the country? It surely includes Momen's party that claims to be secular (blatantly false) but uses 'allahu akbar' as its motto, keeps Islam as the state religion, and promotes and protects Islam in many different ways, including with financing Islamic activities through APD and with laws to punish people who criticize Islam or its inventor, Mohammad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an utter disgrace that too many people in Bangladesh with high academic qualifications, cannot apply their human intelligence, knowledge and rational thinking on religions. Instead, they keep promoting the absurdities, injustices, and hatreds of religions, making the lives of too many innocent people miserable! Bangladesh not only does not need protection and promotion of Islam; it also does not need supporting non-Muslim religious activities. It needs humanity. It needs applications of human intelligence. It needs common senses of good and bad, of right and wrong, of justice and injustice and of compassion and cruelty, for all its citizens to be worthy human beings - to live and let others live with human dignity, rights, peace and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/10-24-who-were-behind-the-recent-heinous-atrocities-on-hindus-in-bangladesh</id>
		<title>Who Were Behind the Recent Heinous Atrocities on Hindus in Bangladesh?</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/10-24-who-were-behind-the-recent-heinous-atrocities-on-hindus-in-bangladesh" />
		<updated>2021-10-24T12:51:12Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Over the last eleven days, Hindus of Bangladesh in many parts of the country have been living under extreme fear and agony. They are also scared to talk about what and who are responsible for the barbaric atrocities upon their community in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the latest episodes of the atrocities on innocent Hindus start? A copy of the principal Islamic religious book of Quran was found on the lap of the idol of the Hindu deity Hanuman in front of a Durga Puja venue in Cumilla in the early morning of October 13, 2021. That was interpreted as an insult on that book not only by the Islamic fanatic citizens of Bangladesh, but also by the police officer who went there after the incident was reported to the police! The Hindus there got scared of what might follow as atrocities on them by senseless Muslim mobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What followed in Bangladesh were not widely reported in the significant newspapers there, as the news media there have a history of self-censoring of news on atrocities on religions minorities by Muslim mobs in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-58999047"&gt;As per a BBC news report on October 22, 2021&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;within hours of the rumor spreading on social media, hundreds of Muslim fundamentalists went on a rampage targeting Hindu religious pavilions in Comilla. Soon, the violence spread to other parts of Bangladesh. Temples were desecrated and hundreds of houses and businesses of the Hindu minority torched. Seven people, including two Hindus, were killed and many more injured in days of violence. Police opened fire and used tear gas in several places to contain the raging mob.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other parts of Bangladesh included Chandpur, where 4 Muslim criminals were killed by police firing on the mobs, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.thedailystar.net/news/bangladesh/news/police-mob-clash-chandpur-death-toll-now-4-2198306?fbclid=IwAR0kOzPZJnYYf--XRkeyqPMU3Dybr1DjNUMdBCbiax5N87F-mm72uD611NY"&gt;Daily Star (Bangladesh) report on October 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;. That report did not talk about the number or names of the innocent Hindu victims!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other parts of the country also included Cox's Bazar, Chandpur, Chattogram, Chapainawabganj and Moulvibazar, &lt;a href="https://bdnews24.com/bangladesh/2021/10/14/police-detain-9-over-attacks-on-puja-venues-hindu-homes-in-coxs-bazar?fbclid=IwAR1wYhq45-FXEV4NQy_dSS7dBdsD0ZzpSO_RPrOVgQ0cOBbH_leLJlJIS2c"&gt;according to a bdnews24.com report on October 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;. Again, the number and names of innocent Hindu victims were not reported. These places are located in the east, north and central parts of Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, according to the same BBC news report, nearly a week after the violence began, dozens of Hindu houses were torched in northern Bangladesh after another social media post alleged that Hindus defamed an Islamic holy place, the government had to deploy security forces in 22 districts to control the riots, and Muslim leaders called for harsh punishments against those who defame Islam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atrocities in northern Bangladesh were reported by the &lt;a href="https://www.thedailystar.net/news/bangladesh/crime-justice/news/shall-we-leave-then-2201341?fbclid=IwAR075s4K8mng-wzPlRyxr8NPyxxlu8FXkANW3vnlzDVvTb4pc8aaPt7b32k"&gt;Daily Star (Bangladesh) on October 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;. According to that report, miscreants (Muslim mobs) set fire to 25 houses and shops owned by poor, innocent and nonviolent Hindus. A total of 66 families were affected by the incident, according to a government agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atrocities by Muslim mobs in Bangladesh also included Chaumuhani, Noakhali, in the central part of Bangladesh. There, two Hindus were killed while Muslim mobs attacked, vandalized, and looted Hindu temples, households, and businesses. This was reported by the Dhaka &lt;a href="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/2021/10/16/hindu-man-found-dead-in-pond-next-to-temple-in-noakhali"&gt;Tribune on October 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based upon news media reports, the atrocities on Hindus by Muslim mobs were widespread in Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent social media reports also included several rapes as well; and they cannot be ruled out just because the self-censoring mainstream newspapers did not report them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the violence, vandalism, torching of properties, hurting people, raping women and girls, and murdering people were done as one-sided atrocities by Muslim mobs upon innocent Hindus. While insulting a book is not a crime in any civilized nation, the crime by Bangladeshi standards, of putting the Quran on the lap of a Hanuman idol, was not done and could not have been done by a believing Hindu. The reality is that the Quran has at least 20 verses that admonish idolatry. The lap is a place for affection, and Quran surely is not a lovable book to an idolator. No believing Hindu would put that book on the lap of the idol of his/her revered monkey. Indeed, it was not done by a Hindu; it was done by a Muslim, obviously to outrage the Muslims who are incapable of rational thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strangely, from all the atrocities, the popular demand in Bangladesh has been to find and punish the people who placed the Quran on Hanuman's lap, a lot more so than to punish the Muslim mob criminals! The idea is that placing the Quran there caused too many Muslims to go crazy. Even the mainstream newspaper, Dhaka Tribune, had the &lt;a href="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/2021/10/22/iqbal-the-man-behind-the-quran-incident-brought-to-comilla"&gt;following news headline&lt;/a&gt; two days back&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iqbal Hossain, key suspect in anti-Hindu violence, brought to Comilla!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comilla is an old spelling of the name of the present district of Cumilla in Bangladesh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But was it really the Quran on Hanuman's lap that turned too many Muslims crazy? If they had common sense, could they have gone insane for that? If they did not have too much of Islamic sentiments, could they have done what they did? My answers to all three questions are &amp;quot;No&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iqbal Hossain and his accomplices played a bad prank; they wanted to provoke the Islamic sentimental fools of Bangladesh. They did not commit vandalism, arson, looting, hurting people, raping, murdering, any kind of crimes that the mobs did. They also did not make the would-be criminals excessively Islamic sentimental. They were not the real culprits behind the atrocities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, who were the real culprits behind the recent heinous crimes by Muslim mobs on innocent and nonviolent Hindus in Bangladesh? My answer to the question is, anyone who put too much of Islamic sentiments in the heads of the majority population of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are the people that put too much of Islamic sentiments in the heads of the Muslim pollution of Bangladesh? Here are a few answers that I can think of. The intellectuals and politicians who promote and protect Islam in Bangladesh. The secular-claiming political party that uses 'Allahu Akbar' as their motto and keeps Islam as the state religion. The secular-claiming prime minister who wants to build more than 500 model mosques in the country. The PhD degree-holding science professor at Dhaka University who uses burqa to show off her Islamic faith. The expatriate scientist living in the West who sends money to Bangladesh to build mosques and madrasas over promoting factual and logical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For not only respecting non-Muslims, but also to bring the Muslims to modernity, promotion and protection of Islam must end in Bangladesh and everywhere else in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-15-world-of-inquiry-muktomona</id>
		<title>World of Inquiry - Muktomona</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-15-world-of-inquiry-muktomona" />
		<updated>2021-09-14T21:14:33Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Guest Writer: Md Maruf Hasan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Call me pig or bastard or name me the worst type of animal in the world. I do not mind. Ernest Hemingway once said, &amp;quot;There is nothing to write. All you do is sit down at a typewriter and bleed&amp;quot;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It was 1964, a French man was announced for the Nobel prize which he refused to accept. It was 2nd July 1961, an American man fixed his   shotgun in the head and committed suicide. A greatest Russian writer left his house at the age of 82 and he was found dead at the railway station with a book. An Algerian &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Nobel Laureate &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;man died in a road accident. A German man ran and shouted and went crazy after looking at the vivid picture of his favorite novel. Another Russian old man finished his last novel portraying a picture saying fathers in the family should not have rights. A French evolutionary biologist died with extreme poverty being neglected by his society. An Arabian man climbed to the mountain and tried to jump off from mountains few times to commit suicide. A man died for his ethics in Greece. Two men were ordered to burn down for their stance. One of them died and one of them is a mystery. A mother with her son had to jump off in the fire for her stance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Humayun Azad &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;was speaking about the myth of Sisyphus. Kierkegaard drew a picture of our life. What about a stoic lifestyle? Why not practicing Taoist or Buddhist style yoga? Why not perform 5 prayers in the mosque? Why not stand for prayer every Sunday in the church? Why not go for Durga puja? What about visiting any night clubs? What about having relationships? What about marrying someone? What about travelling across the world? What about working 12 hours every day and getting one day off? What about watching movies in the cinema with friends? What about picking up coconuts from trees? What about debating with friends? What about reading books? What about writing assignments? What about writing for Muktomona? What about working at the ministry of foreign affairs and calling people &amp;quot;next…next …next&amp;quot; for the token from 8:00 am till 5:00 pm 5 days in a week? (When people ask, we reply &amp;quot;I work in the ministry of foreign affairs and they think as you think, but you deal with the same content for 8 hours for the rest of your life?) Or What about working inside an office and dealing with so many papers assigned by senior Foxes? What about doing marketing standing like a shameless cat? What about doing programming day and night staring at a screen? What about playing computer games for hours? What about working in the paddy field with farmers? What about selling drugs? What about selling guns? What about doing new stuff always? One person asked me, &amp;quot;doing new stuff, but how long? The problem of boredom comes at the end of the day no matter what you do man&amp;quot;. I had no answer. Albert Camus addressed the fact of our life through his philosophy, absurdism. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;What makes our life meaningful? I need to make a long quotation from Einstein for this question: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;How strange a lot of us mortals! Each of us is here for a brief sojourn; for what purpose he knows not, though he sometimes thinks he senses it. But without deeper reflection one knows from daily life that one exists for other people—first of all for those upon whose smiles and well-being our own happiness is wholly dependent, and then for the many, unknown to us, to whose destinies we are bound by the ties of sympathy. A hundred times every day I remind myself that my inner and outer life are based on the labors of other men, living and dead, and that I must exert myself in order to give in the same measure as I have received and am still receiving. I am strongly drawn to a frugal life and am often oppressively aware that I am engrossing an undue amount of the labor of my fellow-men. I regard class distinctions as unjustified and, in the last resort, based on force. I also believe that a simple and unassuming life is good for everybody, physically and mentally. I do not at all believe in human freedom in the philosophical sense. Everybody acts not only under external compulsion but also in accordance with inner necessity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;From his last sentence we can discuss two strong forces. Today I will focus on only one force. The first strong external force is the economy. It is an external force for every single individual who needs to deal with it. Whether you are rich or poor, you must deal with the economy. It determines your status in human society. I was thinking how money and politics are related for our power in society? Camus loved not to be the son of a rich businessman because it will bind his fate with some kind of heavy responsibility, maybe looking after his father's businesses and property, but how about politics? Suppose I am the son of the prime minister. It means I will most probably end up being prime minister in future. That's how we usually see it. In the context of Bangladesh, people dream for their children to be either engineers or doctors. Obviously, it differs. Chasing BCS for graduate students is another daydream among youths. We love to be honored, and we love security. We love stability. We love status. We love to follow trends as our society asks us to do. We do not love anything other than our parents' dream for us since they grew up with hardship with a bad family economy. By the way, even parents become so happy when they give birth to a son since they expect them to be money making machines. On the other hand, their faces become gloomy when they find giving birth to 3-4 daughters and still no boy. Is the economy related to this? Even love is associated with money that we consider as divine. Why does the last boy of class never dare to speak about his love for the first-class girl? At least, I have never seen it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I have observed the last boy of my class. I saw him going backward when all went forward? As if nobody knows him and he also wants to hide himself. For me, the friendship with the last boy of the class is much better than other friends. Just visit their house and see the harsh reality. Obviously not all but most of the cases if you analyze their life and compare the privileged between you and him. The picture would be very clear. I do not mean that you start analyzing from his life background rather I mean to start with the background of their parents and your parents. Why did this student become the last boy in the class? I must be biased in this instance since I am only focusing on economic factors. There are so many factors but somehow everything has a relationship with the economy implicitly or explicitly. My friend got 3.8 CGPA and managed scholarship and he maintained it till his graduation and I said straightforwardly to his face, &amp;quot;It happened because you have no other option otherwise for survival&amp;quot;. He thought for a while and he said, &amp;quot;true&amp;quot; then he lit a cigarette. Do not believe me. Go to the street for inquiry. I am nobody reciting chorus with Emily Elizabeth Dickinson. I will end my writing with the quotation of German philosopher Friedrich Nietzsche:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;"If you wish to strive for peace of soul and pleasure, then believe; if you wish to be a devotee of truth, then inquire."&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://enblog.muktomona.com/2021/09/15/world-of-inquiry-muktomona/maruf-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-28814"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-28814" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/think-mm/enblog-static/web/wp-uploads/2021/09/Maruf-3.jpg" alt="" width="352" height="352" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-15-the-myth-of-religious-fundamentalism</id>
		<title>The Myth of Religious Fundamentalism </title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-15-the-myth-of-religious-fundamentalism" />
		<updated>2021-09-14T20:47:29Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;~ &lt;em&gt;Hrishik Roy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;What do you possibly imagine when I use the term &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;religious extremists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&amp;quot;? Well, possibly you could be thinking of the Crusaders, RSS and even its most cancerous form in recent times ISIS. Now, of course, these are more than legitimate examples of religious extremism as these groups not only think and come to the most genocidal convictions of their faith but even act upon those convictions. But, I would like to challenge the commonly-held notion that it is only those who act upon their intents who are &amp;quot;religious extremists.&amp;quot; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Rather, I think that individuals who choose to hold beliefs which infringe upon the rights of other people or set up a political system which is exclusively dependent on any theological doctrine should be considered religious extremists too. This includes people who want a theocracy without an essence of doubt. Now, why do I make this claim? Why do I want to stamp people with an obnoxious label as &amp;quot;religious extremists&amp;quot; just for the sake of &amp;quot;thought-crime&amp;quot; i.e. only for their intents and not deeds? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The answer is because such thoughts or intentions and their subsequent propagation have consequences. To delve further into this, I want you to think about the people leaving Bangladesh to escape for Afghanistan after the Taliban takeover. What do you think instigates these individuals to commit such atrocities? It is the tacit acceptance of the Taliban's actions by the general masses. Now, of course, not every Muslim agrees with everything the Taliban does and indeed followers of the faith are not monolithic and I do not intend to paint all Muslims or Hindus or Christians to be extremists here. Please hold your horses before accusing me of a hasty generalization. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;However, here are a few facts I want you to consider: About one-third of the population of my country (Bangladesh) thinks that it is absolutely morally legitimate to kill apostates as in someone who has denounced the religion in public. This may come off as shocking but the figures are even more shocking in different countries according to Pew Research Centre: 60% of the population in Egypt, one-third again in Malaysia and I could go on from here. As a matter of fact, there are about ten countries in this world who have this practice embedded in their law. But the fact of the matter is that there is indeed an inherent problem here- the problem of tacit extremism. This implicit acceptance of extremism is what in fact fuels the people towards more extreme religious interpretation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;While yes, liberal Muslims will claim &amp;quot;That is not real Islam,&amp;quot; and that may be a valid claim because the scriptures are always open to interpretation. But, who really represents Islam then? The liberal Muslims living in the West who think that there is nothing wrong with gay people and ex-Muslims, or the scholars and theologians of Al-Azhar University who have spent almost their entire life studying the scriptures and its practices and want to execute apostates and stone gay people? As a matter of fact, the scholarly consensus among all four schools of Sunni Islamic thought are very clear that both apostasy is to be punished by the death penalty.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Part of the problem here to begin with is that this is not like just one whacky Texan who wants to kill people over not accepting Christ; rather this is more than a significant part of the population who want to establish a theocracy while squashing the rights of minority groups. Yes, they might not explicitly support the Taliban but they do hold more than very problematic principles which they derive from scripture as mentioned above and those principles do align with that of the Taliban. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The only wall of separation between religious nutjobs killing my non-religious friends over blasphemy or imprisoning them are the current laws which prevent them from doing so. These laws are often broken in the name of protecting the divine- as was done by the killers of Avijit Roy and other bloggers. Now you can imagine how worse it will be in a theocracy or a state imposing religious laws; just take a look at Pakistan, Egypt or KSA- all three of which are a prison of a closed society and fit right into the definition of a Hobbesian state. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;If individuals in such large masses hold such viewpoints, it is fairly obvious that the number of people who act upon those will also be greater which is what we essentially tend to see such as in the killing of the French teacher Samuel Paty for the &amp;quot;crime&amp;quot; of showing blasphemous cartoons to students. The killer received massive support all across my country with millions going out into the streets to riot against the French government's freedom of expression and boycotts were planned out. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;What liberal Muslims in the West, such as Mehdi Hassan, do not realize is that it is not just a fringe minority of the population who think that it is okay to kill blasphemers but rather this is a large chunk of the population and the radix malorum is the absolutist nature of the faith itself based on two impossible ideas- the perfect book and the perfect man. A massive part of the problem is that the canonical scriptures are mostly believed to be historically accurate word to word and therefore any objection or bad-mouthing of those books is by definition profane and thus the absolute nature often prevents or discourages criticism by Muslim reformers by framing such criticisms out. Unless that source of extremism itself is acknowledged, it is impossible to solve the problem through denialism. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The reason of this denialism from liberal Muslims can also be partially attributed to the rise of anti-Muslim bigotry in the post 9/11 period and the large scale demonization of Muslims. Due to the hostility propagated by the Western right-wing (who actually agree with the right-wing Islamic theocrats on various issues such as marriage equality: just under different frameworks), any criticism of the religion and the condemnation of the actions of its adherents have been deemed to be racist and thus disassociated from the faith. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;However, the fact is that people do hold largely problematic views about apostates and simply saying that the problem is not the scripture which actively condones hostility towards gays and apostates is like saying Catholic Church hierarchs had no connection in leading Medieval peasants to slaughter Jews and Muslims during the crusades. Saying that Islamism (a political movement to establish an Islamic theocracy) has nothing to do with Islam (the broader religion), while the former directly derives its precept from the latter, is categorically misleading.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A very similar case can also be made out of Hinduism which in more recent times has also gone onto become overtly cancerous under the widely celebrated banner of Hindutva- the ideal Hindu state which diminishes the rights of gender minorities and lower castes through the implementation of a primitive and rigid social hierarchy based on scriptures such as Manusmriti. It needs to be understood that BJP and RSS are also &amp;quot;religious extremists&amp;quot; according to the definition I am arguing for and need to be held accountable for the atrocities they instigate accordingly. A lot of liberal Hindus also do not understand that these precepts are directly derived from scriptures and thus fail to acknowledge that such a problem may exist. However, burying your head in the sand does nothing more than keep the problem unchecked. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The reason why I initially argued for the expansion of the definition of &amp;quot;religious extremists&amp;quot; to include people who passively support extremism is because it helps us to realize and track the actual sources of these extreme beliefs and admit them accordingly. Acknowledging that religious fundamentalism is not just a myth but rather communities can and do hold bad viewpoints at large and not dismissing the experiences of those who suffered- dissenters and gender or sexual minorities - can help us go a long way in achieving peace and religious harmony. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="references"&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;BBC News. (2020, October 27). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Huge Bangladesh rally calls for boycott of French products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-54704859&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Monk, P. (2016, August 12). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Muslims in the West must reject al-Azhar imam's apostasy views&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;. The Austalian. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;https://www.theaustralian.com.au/commentary/opinion/muslims-in-the-west-must-reject-a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;lazhar-imams-apostasy-views/news-story/361d44e4c7b83044864899e73263db1d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Some of the rulings on apostasy and apostates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;. (n.d.). Islam Question &amp;amp; Answer. Retrieved September 14, 2021, from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;https://islamqa.info/en/categories/very-important/24/answers/14231/some-of-the-rulings on-apostasy-and-apostates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Wormald, B. (2013, April 30). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Chapter 1: Beliefs About Sharia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;. Pew Research Center's Religion &amp;amp; Public Life Project. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;https://www.pewforum.org/2013/04/30/the-worlds-muslims-religion-politics-society-beliefs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;-about-sharia/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-13-happy-birthday-avi</id>
		<title>Happy birthday Avi!</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-13-happy-birthday-avi" />
		<updated>2021-09-13T17:58:30Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy birthday Avi! You would be 50 today if you were here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/think-mm/enblog-static/web/wp-uploads/2021/09/Avi-a-few-minutes-prior.jpeg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is our last picture, someone (don't know who) took it 20-30 min before the attack on Feb 26th, 2015, inside the boimela. Avi got us some samosas as we were getting hungry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-04-crisis-of-god-in-21st-century-and-some-thoughts-on-writings-of-avijit-roy</id>
		<title>Crisis of God in 21st Century and Some Thoughts on Writings of Avijit Roy</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/09-04-crisis-of-god-in-21st-century-and-some-thoughts-on-writings-of-avijit-roy" />
		<updated>2021-09-04T17:18:56Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Guest Writer, Md Maruf Hasan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;In 21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;st&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; century, the world is moving forward recklessly like Voyager 1 and 2. Human civilization has peaked at its highest level of exploration, yet biological evolution of living organisms is taught as just theory despite having mountains of evidences in Bangladesh and other religious countries. The question is for what? The answer in simple manner is because of religious virus that was addressed by Avijit Roy in his various writings. Avijit Roy, a decent and ordinary student and teacher, just boldly spoke about his mind about the nature of the universe based on science and reason. As a new reader of Muktomona bloggers, I find no contradictory statement at his writings and I find enough references provided to justify their stance. I do not understand what justification was used to kill him. I have walked both bank of the Padma River and I saw sincerity of both sides. Both sides of river have no alternative but to break and build new way and both banks of the river are helpless to the strong current. All they can is to support the current and make way for the flowing river. Universe does not care anyone's existence. Universe will move on as it is and our way of understanding about the universe makes no difference to the universe. We learn from our mistakes from the universe by making mistakes times and again, but universe is as it is. Thousands of reformers have been passed throughout human history and everyone has to accept the inevitable truth. Out of approximately 13.77 billion years after the big bang, we are here only by chance for about 50-60 solar years in this planet and then everyone of us has to leave this planet forever. Our beliefs have no effect at all in this inevitable fate. Our fame, status, wealth, race, color have no effect at our universal fate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Can we stop the flow of Padma River? well, you can change the direction if you build a bridge and create new way for the river but it is impossible to stop the flow of the river. And building a bridge and creating a new way is not an easy task. You need enormous courage and you need action most importantly. For thousands of years, philosophers, religious leaders, political leaders came and tried in their own way to change the flow by building the bridge and by creating new way. We have seen scientists have little to say considering they were weak force in society. But last 1000 years in human history something miraculous happened that was beyond the comprehension of philosophers, religious leaders and political leaders. We are lucky enough to see the progress of scientific revolution where scientific worldview became de facto world view in this current world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Let's say we disagree with scientific worldview, but in reality, you have no better alternative when you start understanding the nature of the universe. Due to enormous research better theories are coming and the way of our new understanding about the universe is developing. Despite changing thoughts in science, we have more reliability and hope in science than any religious jargon that we have been taught for last thousands of years. We urge to go beyond the border to explore. We die in the street while walking but we ask our fellow not to stop walking as Avijit Roy shouted towards his fellow mates. Maybe thousands of obstacles, but we choose to walk along. Maybe nobody is with you but you still decide to keep on walking. We lost our guardians and we have finished our last food of the day, but we have still decided to walk along the mountainous path till last breath. Maybe there will be nobody sitting next to you during your death in the street, but you can lie down facing at the sky and starring at night sky with full of stars and our milky way galaxy line. You spoke the truth and you died with truth Dr. Avijit Roy instead of being hypocrites like millions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;In recent time, pseudo-critical analyst Abu Talha Muhammad Adnan was missing and later it was known that it was just a drama and the motif behind this is very clear and that is he wanted to spread his ideology through this technique and he became famous by nights among general students of Bangladesh on YouTube. He was talking about Islamic messianism that every major religion has in the world. I wonder about his education in department of philosophy. He is diverting the thoughts of philosophers saying Jew's propaganda. He is introducing big terms in vague manner and in reality, he understands little what he is talking about and the entire young generation response was positive towards him since they also never heard those terms previously and All praised at him. It is like donkeys are praising at donkey for giving jump at muddy shallow water thinking deep water for swimming. Those, who read western literature of last few centuries, know the ideologies we have today came from being antagonist behavior towards orthodoxy church in Europe. Martin Luther is the first name we can utter. Then we know all the scientists who were accused of being heretic for their writings. Then, we know about an innocent girl, Anna frank's diary how nationalism and religions undermine an innocent girl's inner feeling just because she was born as Jews and she had to die at the age of 15. Where was your morality? Where was your human values? We killed Anna Frank. We all are responsible for her death. We know about Darwin, Karl Marx, Sigmund Freud, Nietzsche, David Hume, Russel, Richard Dawkins, Sam Harris, Late Cristopher Hitchens. Their writings were not about conspiracy against Islam that Abu Talha Muhammad Adnan misinterpreted by referring to messianism being antisemitic to his audiences. Every society has good and bad people, but you cannot kill everyone and spread hatred against entire race. That's how nationalism and religions promote hatred among our fellow human beings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;There is another pseudo-critical analyst in Bangladesh Mufti Kazi Ibrahim who claims not to talk anything beyond Quran and Sunnah. In reality all his analysis is just based on his mere wishful thinking. The good example is Greek people who remembered stars by making them think like different animal shapes so that they can remember the position of stars. You do not need to be expert to understand the hypocritical lectures of Mufti Kazi Ibrahim who is possessed by his self-centered knowledge. Will he correct his stance? Never ….as he said in his TV interview in recent time. Even if God of Muhammad comes, he will still worship himself instead of God of Muhammad. This is the danger of self-confident about religious educated people. Only one, who speaks deserves to enter paradise since he is in right understanding as these people think at their mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;For thousands of years, religious texts have been analyzed in the same way and each scholar who holds the authority for years of study can only be considered as best man for interpretation of that texts even though the interpretation and understanding are wrong. Religious people are famous for blind acceptance. You wear a religious dress and walk along the way in unknown city in Bangladesh and then you would realize how people respect you in the street even though you were the worst type of man at your village. From practical experience, once a student, who recently finished his memorization of Quran, went to a mosque in different village and Imam got so scared looking at student's white dress up and his innocent looking face with full of beard. Imam invited him to give speech in Jumma prayer and the student proudly went forward and started to give speech before people and said in Bengali, &amp;quot;God has said in his book seeking knowledge is compulsory for every Muslim&amp;quot;. The student does not even know that the statement is in the hadith and not in the Quran since he does not understand Quran. Hence, he could not make differences between what is hadith and what is Quran.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The problem with education system in Bangladesh they neither have proper knowledge about their religions nor they have proper knowledge about science. Even science teachers teach evolution as just theory being scared losing his job or reputation or maybe called as atheist. Teachers says in class &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;They claim&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; how evolution happened in plants and animals. &amp;quot;The reality is, like Gould you need to confess the concept non-overlapping magisteria (NOMA) or you have no way but to accept saying evolution makes sense. The theist like Collins cannot avoid the fact of evolution making sense even though he believes in Christian God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We just want to understand the truth of the universe as students. We want to read all books and let us compare the ideas independently by ourselves. You want hide truth from upcoming young generations by banning books and killing people who never harassed and raped any girls and never celebrated century of rape like others? Where is your analysis if you speak truth? Provide us with your arguments with evidences if you claim you speak right. The reality is you talk about fairy tales to satisfy yourself at the first place. The reality is you worship your own reasonings and you never worshipped or interested to deliver the sincere message of Muhammad on tawhid. You are the greatest liars and you claim to speak the obvious truth by referring to messianism? Did Muhammad mention the timing period? Even Angel Gabriel in Islamic narrative has no idea but you predict the time by saying I have vast knowledge about Quran and Sunnah and recent books? And each time you predict, it turns out to be wrong. You just want to promote your stupid ideologies not the ideology of Muhammad. You want to portray yourself as the smartest and deep thinker among people, but in reality, you are just smart fools like magicians do. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;When we think about Muhammad, we know that Islam is all about sincerity towards Allah as Bukhari started narration indicating importance of sincerity for God. The writings of so-called atheists (as you call Jew's propaganda) Avijit Roy, Darwin, Karl Marx, Nietzsche, Freud, Russel, Dostoevsky, Camus, Jean Paul Sartre much better in sincerity than you hypocrites who want to satisfy himself by referring to Allah and his messengers. You even do not have sense of shame and regret for what you are speaking by the name of Allah. This is you who are misrepresenting Allah, not atheists, not Jews. You justify your stance by referring to Quran and hadith and that's exactly what Al-Kaieda did after 9/11 attacks. Abu Bakar burned all of his writings fearing if he gives any of his opinion in the words by mistake and you give your opinion by saying Muhammad said this and that just to justify your pseudo-prediction. Abu Bakar was the man who treated God as God as he deserves. Umar did understand the message what Muhammad was talking about (weather it is truth or false that's the different discussion). That's why he said famously &amp;quot;I wish I were dust and I was never born in this planet&amp;quot;. The modern understanding on God is more explicit in nature after Nietzsche addressing about God at &amp;quot;Thus Spoke Zarathustra&amp;quot;. This is not about God anymore and this is more than that and Samuel Backet famously portrayed that in his drama &amp;quot;Waiting for Godot&amp;quot;. No God was, is, will be for us waiting in the heaven for any accountability as guardian and we will not be subjected as criminals for our actions. Robert Frost harshly portrayed the fact in his poem in modern American literature,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&amp;quot;I turned to speak to God About the world's despair but to make bad matters worse I found God wasn't there. God turned to speak to me (Don't anybody laugh) God found I wasn't there At least not over half.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Huxley's novel &amp;quot;Brave New World' mentioned the modern crisis of humans for God. Not sure if, Jesus, Moses, Muhammad, Umar and Abu Bakar would be happy by hearing the news that scientific worldview wanted to say about God today. Each philosopher or religious leader was against the surrounding people of that particular society as we learn from history or from their biography. In today's context, the problem never revolves around does God exist or not? The problem never revolves around messianism in current context in multicultural world. The problem is more than that and bloggers want to shout out loudly, &amp;quot;We can be wrong, but teach us with your research-based knowledge and information. Do not kill us&amp;quot;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Let's talk about LGBT community, DNA is responsible for gay behavior, but religious teachers in male dominated madrasah in Bangladesh are more involved of raping young boys as recent news came in. Not everyone is born with gay behavior in their DNA so far, I understood. The religious teachers they do have wife or they can get married, if not married yet, according to Shariya law. Tell me how many reports have been lodged against gay activists who raped young boys like Madrasah teachers are doing continuously. God destroyed the nation of Lot because they did extreme by forcing everyone in society (They wanted to rape angels also as Old Testament and Quran tell us). Same like Madrasah teachers are doing with these innocent children and these Madrasah teachers should be destroyed by God in current context if you really talk about gay sins, not LGBT community. This sin was never major sin like sin of tawhid in Islam (There is famous hadith in Islamic narrative saying every sin will be forgiven except sin of associating partner with God) and only Islamic government will take action of these people as we find in Islamic Jurisprudence. Then, why did you kill Xulhaz Mann? Why do not you kill those imams? You are not promoting your Islam rather you are destroying Islam and you are worst type of hypocrites of Islam that mentioned in Quran. Indeed, you deserve the lowest hell of Islam.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;As for the message of new atheism that I read in Avijit Roy's book and it seemed New atheism in 21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;st&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; century promotes how people can make meaning of their life and live peacefully in society as shown by giving example of Sweden and other atheist countries in Avijit Roy's writings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Richard Dawkins, late Cristopher Hitchens, Avijit Roy did have family and they lead absolutely meaningful life with moral values without being dependent on religions. Thomas Hobbes, Rousseau mentioned the importance of social contract in order to bring peace and harmony in society. I would say this is atheist-phobia for religious people thinking atheists are worst types of evolving animals who do not follow Religions and orders, but in reality, this is completely opposite. You need to talk and mix up with them and see how they will not kill you just because of your ideas rather they will argue with you in the best manner to come up with better understanding about reality and life. In Quran, it is asking you to argue and convince your ideas in the best manner and the duty of Muhammad was to convey the message not to regulate people like police and just kill people who hold different views and Quran do speak about religious tolerance if others do not accept Islam. Why do you want to kill a Jews, Christian, Hindu, atheist if they speak bad about Islam? They have right to scold this religion as stupid and your duty is to give logical arguments not scolding rather giving good arguments with decent words, but what you did is directly giving fatwa to kill someone. Salman Rushdie once said that even Muhammad would agree with me I think what I was talking about the problem in Muslim society. The question is do they scold every day? The answer is &amp;quot;No&amp;quot;. They just wanted to explain certain situation to show their views to show our shortcomings, and you may disagree and keep on arguing and you produce intellectual works as they do, but where is your intellectual works or analysis? You just want to kill and die as &amp;quot;shahid&amp;quot;. You are explicitly coward and lazy and you are not following the major instruction of your God in Islam. What Abu Talha Muhammad Adnan and Mufti Kazi Ibrahim are doing, those activities will be considered much better than yours though they are spreading pseudo-religious ideas. If you really want to speak about any topic, you gather the enough information with evidences and express your views. It is fine if you do mistakes but you can improve your arguments by providing more information and resources, but your religious people are dumb and lazy and stubborn that you want anything blame to leave for Allah and Muhammad. And your analysis is so narrow since you do not like reading books, rather you just love to copy and paste and get fatwa from someone and go to kill someone and later love to die as Shahid. Such easy path you want to be &amp;quot;shahid&amp;quot;.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Last but not least, it seemed the goal of new atheism drastically differs from nationalist propaganda or race superiority. It encourages you to use your knowledge and develop your understanding based on science and reason. Martin Luther once said, &amp;quot;Here I stand, I can do no other,&amp;quot;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/08-27-is-bangladeshi-government-threat-for-individual-liberty</id>
		<title>Is Bangladeshi Government Threat for Individual  Liberty?</title>
		<link href="https://en.muktomona.com/posts/2021/08-27-is-bangladeshi-government-threat-for-individual-liberty" />
		<updated>2021-08-26T20:06:35Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;~ &lt;em&gt;By Guest Writer: Md Maruf Hasan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Taslima Nasrin seems quite right at her outspoken accusations in terms of religious countries when she raised issue at her various writings about individual liberty in the pseudo-religious countries like Bangladesh. Recent media reports on prominent female actresses and women leaders can be seen major trends in Bangladeshi news and social media. Most of the young citizens find Bangladeshi news entertaining, especially when we look at the comment sections of these videos on YouTube. Young people mostly tried to see from religious perspectives leaving vulgar words full of hatred and jealousy accusing the hedonistic lifestyle of aristocrat families and government officials tend to look at it from a legal stance. Politicians look at it from a political stance. Each victim is claiming as a conspiracy against them before media while some victims are just silent in front of media like the issue of Bashundhara MD Sayem's scandal. I do not want to delve into any of these issues. The hypocrisy of these agencies and people are clearly visible as soon as we analyze these incidents using the Freudian and Marxist approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;However, my concern is individual liberty as for recent incidents. I do not think the government is working in the right direction when it comes to the individual liberty of common citizens. Most of the reports came out in media in which the focus of video content was on alcoholic drinks and prominent women and their families. They utter as being victims and unethical, especially interview of Helena's daughter as representative of Bangladeshi upcoming young generation. The question arises in my mind should government agencies need to rectify their ethics during investigation since the salary is paid by citizens to serve citizens? For years there was no report whatsoever about any prominent figures, but recently the trend is very high. The problem is these are the aristocratic class in our society and they should deserve their liberty since Bangladesh is not a communist country and the government should not interfere with anyone's private room if she drinks Vodka or water. What they did recently it was even not allowed under the totalitarian Islamic regime led by Muhammad and his companions. As I have observed there is nothing wrong with selling and buying alcoholic drinks in Muslim tourist countries like Malaysia. In a secular state, a citizen has the right to how she or he wants to live with her and his personal beliefs. In other words, she or he can be practicing Muslim, Hindu, Buddha, atheist, agnostics or moderate Muslim, Hindu, Buddha, atheist, agnostics as long as they do not harm others being fundamentalists. The issue of Pori Moni has been diverted for sure and her liberty and right have been systematically ridiculed. The comments section of those videos on YouTube showed how she was accused of being characterless. This should not be any of their business in a secular country when it is about her body. Women must clear their stance. As a citizen, she has the right to raise her concern if she feels threaten or feels harassed. This is exactly the issue of marital rape that our women, mothers and sisters, in religious society cannot talk about. Those who accused of her being characterless are mostly saying out of jealousy and due to lack of sex as Sigmund Freud tells us. In other words, it exposes open hypocrisy by the name of religion. At the end of the day almost everyone is involved with pornographic content in internet regardless their religious status as far as recent research has shown. Anyone who does try to search about this issue can get a clear picture just by doing cursory search. Anyone who has read Kafka's "The Trial" and "The Castle" knows what's going on with these recent incidents. Yes, the accusations came in the reports saying these individuals are causing trouble to others, nobody would disagree with the government in this instance, but to investigate those accusations, you are entering someone's private room and harassing their family members in front of the nation and making them as sexual object and object of lust before young viewers as we read comments on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;In recent years, we have noticed Government is highly concerned to eradicate all types of drugs and pornographic content in Bangladesh to eliminate moral degradation, but the religious content in the national education curriculum is very little and corruption among bureaucrats is not a new phenomenon at all. Despite the concept War on Drugs, US could not control but country like Switzerland by legalizing drug in a systematic manner they have reduced drug consumption better than any other countries that started War on Drugs. Why do not we see this one as disease and try to cure systematically. We can learn from Switzerland. I would not comment about politicians since the nation knows their angelic characteristics regardless of Opposition and Government parties. How do you expect to build a nation with moral values when we neither teach them secular or religious values properly? We are, in fact, educated in pseudo-religious and pseudo-secular values and we tend to hate both values thinking hypocritical and meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;The accusation came from opposition parties for years saying the ruling Government is working like fascists and Nazis. However, I would appreciate the massive developmental work of the ruling government across Bangladesh and we have seen how our honorable Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina did not consider any type of corruption even if it is found among her party's leaders. The way she chose ministers after the last election is really admirable and I think despite some shortcomings as humans these people deserve to rule these ministries and they did more efficiently compared to the opposition parties. In fact, the less corruption happened ever in the history after 1971s among the current government's ministries as far as I am concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;My focal point for today's discussion is when we promote a country as a secular country, the government should not interfere anyone's personal bedroom or at least should have some ethics when an investigation is going on, perhaps, asking every single member should be outside of the house during an investigation and not being rude to any individual because the mental trauma can affect the person's psychology in the long run. This is a shame for the government of Bangladesh when they say to the international community saying we promote secularism in the state as far as I came across Aljazeera's interview with Mehdi in "Head to Head". Once you analyze and try to decode these recent events from Freudian and Marxist perspectives, you can realize how dubious these issues are. Same goes with recent scandals of religious leaders. Sexuality is inherently with every individual's unconscious mind. Those who are accusing others at the end of the day are not out of evolving animals. What kind of hypocrisy are you talking about then when you are one of them? All will be considered nothing but absolutely hypocrisy by the name of law and religion. If you discuss openly these issues, everything will be transparent. Even the word "hypocrisy" will be meaningless if we talk from Nietzsche's point of view in post-modern context . In short, certain acts seem right for the government when we see their various involvements with different crimes, but at the same time media, government officials should be held accountable if these activities undermine other citizen's individual liberty. At the end of the day we are in grey world since only ruling government in each country will define what's right and what's wrong instead of dead God of Nietzsche. Wherever you look at ,you would only find pure hypocrisy by the name of religion. To them, God is indeed a hungry dog in the street and it is a matter of choice if you would throw a piece of bread. That's the nature of religious people towards their personal God. What morality are you talking about then? All we see is drama by expert actors from Shakespearean perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional Tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pori moni&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
		<summary>MuktoMona English Writers Corner</summary>
	</entry>
</feed>